Filip Pagliaro

Stockholm

Professional Summary _

Software engineer with enterprise full-stack experience in TypeScript and React. Most recently designed and implemented an internal API Management platform that streamlined integration processes across teams. Also enjoys experimenting with Generative AI and building video games on the side.

Experience ____

Accenture Sweden, Software Engineer

 Designed and implemented internal API management platform for client, including developer tooling, CI/CD pipelines, and platform services.

(Azure, Github Actions, Powershell, TypeScript, .Net)

• Designed and implemented new features for mobile app, backend, and web plat-

(TypeScript, React-Native, Node.js, Firebase)

• Implementation and maintenance of new features for client's e-commerce plat-

(Typescript, React, Jest, Git, Azure DevOps)

Uppsala University, Teaching Assistant – Haskell

- Helped students understand Haskell and programming concepts
- Ran lab sessions and supported students one-on-one with debugging and problemsolving

Stockholm, Sweden Aug 2023 - Present

Uppsala, Sweden Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

Education

MSc **Uppsala University**, Computer and Information Engineering

Master's thesis on Multi-agent Reinforcement Learning

Bachelor's thesis on Image Classification using CNNs

Politecnico di Milano, Computer Engineering

Exchange Semester

Uppsala, Sweden

Sept 2018 – Jun 2023

Milan, Italy Sept 2022 – Jan 2023

Technical Skills _____

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java, C/C++, C#, PowerShell, Haskell

Frameworks & Tools: Node.js, React, .NET

DevOps & Cloud: Docker, Azure, Firebase, GitHub Actions

Machine Learning: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, Pandas, NumPy, OpenCV, Hugging Face Transformers, Gen Al APIs (OpenAl, Ollama)

Collaboration & Professional Skills: Effective communication, Cross-functional teamwork, Agile collaboration, Technical problem-solving, Code reviews & mentoring

Languages ______

Swedish Native **English** Fluent Italian Intermediate